Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Jack Peters Papers, 1965-1989 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Meetings, 1980-1989 and undated, (7 boxes)
  - Managers meetings
    - 1984 Apr. 11, Atlanta (Box 71)
    - 1984 June 7, Chicago (Box 71)
    - 1984 Aug. 30 (Box 71)
    - 1984 Nov. 29 (Box 71)
    - 1985 Feb. 14, Detroit (Box 71)
    - 1985 May 7, Water Club, (2 folders) (Box 71)
    - 1985 Aug. 7 (Box 72)
    - 1986 Feb. 11 (Box 72)
  - Media Leadership Workshop, 1984-1985, (2 folders) (Box 72)
  - Operations Committee, 1984-1985, (4 folders) (Box 72)
  - Operations Management Group meetings
    - General files, 1986-1987 (Box 72)
    - 1986 May 7, (2 folders) (Box 72)
    - 1986 Aug. 14, (2 folders) (Box 72)
    - 1986 Sept. 10, (2 folders) (Box 72)
  - Professional Development Group, 1984-1986 (Box 73)
  - Proprietary Association
    - 1985 Apr., Breakers-Palm Beach meeting (Box 73)
    - 1986 May, annual meeting (Box 73)
  - Sam Meek seminars, 1985-1986 (Box 73)
  - Seminars, 1984-1985 (Box 73)
  - Talent, 1985-1986 (Box 73)
  - U.S. Spot Study meeting, 1985 Sept., (2 folders) (Box 73)
  - Veterans of Foreign Wars meeting, 1986 May 4 (Box 73)
  - Washington, D.C., State Department Luncheon, 1986 June 17 (Box 73)
  - World Advertising Forum, EPCOT, 1984 May (Box 73)
  - World Managers Meeting, 1980 June 6 (Box 73)
  - James Young seminars, 1984, 1986 (Box 73)
- New Business, 1981-1987, (3 boxes)
  Contains scripts, plans, meeting files, and research related to JWT new accounts prospects, including scripts of general agency presentations, marketing and acquisitions plans, and new business reports from JWT regional domestic offices. Original folder titles were maintained and items arranged alphabetically.
  - General files, 1983-1986, (2 folders) (Box 74)
  - Account planning, 1983-1987, (4 folders) (Box 74)
  - Account planning, behavior research, 1985 (Box 74)
  - Acquisitions, 1981-1986 (Box 74)
  - Acquisition Plan, 1981 (Box 74)
  - Advertising Managers Group, 1987 Plan (Box 74)
  - California Project, 1984-1985 (Box 75)
  - JWT Presentation Book: About You and Us, undated (Box 75)
  - Marketing Modeling, 1986 (Box 75)
  - Marketing plans, 1985-1987, (4 folders) (Box 75)
  - New Business Status, 1982-1983 (Box 75)
  - Planning, 1986-1987, (2 folders) (Box 75)
  - Regional
    - Atlanta, 1984-1986 (Box 75)
    - Chicago, 1984-1986 (Box 75)
    - Detroit, 1986 (Box 76)
    - Los Angeles, 1983-1986 (Box 76)
    - New York, 1985-1987 (Box 76)
    - San Francisco, 1984-1987 (Box 76)
    - Washington, D.C., 1984-1986 (Box 76)
  - Three-Year Plan, 1986 (Box 76)
- Personnel Files, 1980-1987 and undated, (8 boxes)
  Series includes materials on JWT personnel organization and management, employee biographies, transfers and statistics, as well as files on individual salaries, benefits and loans. The series has been divided into Open and Closed subseries.
  - Open
    Contains general information and blank forms relating to personnel policies for use by JWT managers. Original folder titles were maintained and items were arranged alphatebically.
    - Bonus and Dividend Policy, 1981-1984 (Box 76)
    - Employee benefits, 1984-1987, (3 folders) (Box 76)
    - Employee Benefits Bulletin, 1984 (Box 76)
    - Employee Benefits Review, 1984 (Box 76)
    - Employee evaluation forms, blank, 1981-1984 (Box 76)
    - Employee loan procedures, 1982 (Box 76)
    - Employee Stock Ownership Plan, 1985 (Box 76)
    - Employee stock options, 1985-1986 (Box 76)
    - Human Resources material, 1980 (Box 77)
    - International organization, 1981-1985 (Box 77)
    - International staffing, 1981 (Box 77)
    - International transfers, 1984 (Box 77)
    - Los Angeles, Monthly Manager Assessment Report, 1987 (Box 77)
    - Management succession, 1986 (Box 77)
    - New managers information, 1984-1986 (Box 77)
    - New York Office
      - Company car allowances, 1985 (Box 77)
      - Employee Attitude Study, 1984-1987, (3 folders) (Box 77)
      - JWT Stalemate, undated (Box 77)
      - Managers' Monthly Assessments, 1986 (Box 77)
      - Professional development, 1984-1986 (Box 77)
    - Peer reviews, logistics, 1985 (Box 77)
    - Personnel conference, 1985 (Box 77)
    - Personnel Information Report, 1980 (Box 77)
    - Policy on Political and Government Assignments, 1985 (Box 77)
    - Professional Development at J. Walter Thompson Company, 1985 (Box 78)
    - Professional Incentive Plan (PIP), 1985-1986, (2 folders) (Box 78)
    - Recruitment and Retention of Entry Level Professionals, 1985 (Box 78)
    - Regional Directors, 1985 (Box 78)
    - Regional Financial Director, 1985 (Box 78)
    - Regional Managers Study
      - General files, 1983-1984 (Box 78)
      - Final Report, 1985 (Box 78)
    - Retirement Program, 1986 (Box 78)
    - Retirement Trust
      - General files, 1986, (2 folders) (Box 78)
      - Bank statements, 1986-1987, (2 folders) (Box 78)
      - Meeting, 1986 July (Box 78)
      - Summary Reports, 1986 Apr. (Box 78)
    - Seminars, 1984-1987 (Box 78)
    - Things We Have Learned About Employee Attitude Surveys, 1981 (Box 79)
    - Thompson Achievement Awards Program (TAAP), 1983-1986, (2 folders) (Box 79)
    - Thompson Award Alternative Plan, 1985 (Box 79)
    - Thompson Group policies, 1983-1986 (Box 79)
    - Thompson Incentive Program, 1985 (Box 79)
    - Tom Sutton International Exchange Program, 1985 (Box 79)
    - U.S. personnel, 1984-1986 (Box 79)
  - Restricted Files
    Contains biographical information, clippings, salary figures, and correspondence pertaining to specific employees. Also includes completed surveys and management performance evaluations. Items are arranged alphabetically by office location and, when available, employee last name.
    - General files, 1981-1987, (6 folders) (Box 80)
    - Asia Pacific, 1982-1986 (Box 80)
    - Atlanta Office
      - General files, 1984 (Box 80)
      - Bob Jones, 1985 (Box 80)
      - Jim Pollack, 1984, 1987 (Box 80)
    - Bonus payments, 1981-1986 (Box 80)
    - Chicago Office (Box 81)
      - General files, 1984-1986 (Box 81)
      - Salary file, 1984 (Box 81)
    - Detroit
      - General files, 1982-1987 (Box 81)
      - Glen Niemi, 1983 (Box 81)
      - Peter Schweitzer, 1986 Apr. 14 (Box 81)
    - European offices
      - General files, 1986-1987 (Box 81)
      - Michael Cooper-Evans, 1986-1987 (Box 81)
      - European Superstars and Stars, 1986 (Box 81)
    - Evaluations, 1985 (Box 81)
    - International transfers, 1986 (Box 81)
    - Latin America, circa 1986 (Box 81)
    - Los Angeles
      - General files, 1984-1986 (Box 81)
      - Jim Agnew, 1984-1986 (Box 81)
      - Donald Sullivan, 1986, (2 folders) (Box 81)
    - Management Performance Evaluation Program, 1984 (Box 82)
    - New York Office
      - Chuck Balestrino, 1985 (Box 82)
      - Rena Bartos, 1984 (Box 82)
      - Bob Beauregard, 1987 (Box 82)
      - Tom Benghauser, 1986 (Box 82)
      - Bonuses and incentives, 1983-1987 (Box 82)
      - Steve Bowen, 1985-1986 (Box 82)
      - Joe Brouillard, 1985 (Box 82)
      - Bucky Buchanan, 1985 (Box 82)
      - Gerry Coveny, 1982 (Box 82)
      - Employee Loans, 1984-1986 (Box 82)
      - Evaluations, 1984-1986 (Box 82)
      - Byron Hackett, 1985 (Box 82)
      - Richard Kostrya, 1983-1986 (Box 82)
      - Denis Lanigan, 1986-1987 (Box 82)
      - Management Succession Planning, 1985-1986 (Box 82)
      - Tom Martens, 1986 (Box 82)
      - Bert Metter, 1984 (Box 82)
      - Susan Mirsky, 1986 (Box 82)
      - Wally O'Brien, 1986 (Box 82)
      - Jim Patterson, 1985-1987 (Box 82)
      - Lee Preschel, 1986 (Box 82)
      - Salary file, 1983-1985 (Box 82)
      - Salary information, 1985-1987 (Box 82)
      - Joe Schulte, 1986 (Box 82)
      - Titles, 1984-1986 (Box 82)
      - David Wilken, 1986-1987 (Box 82)
    - Office nominations, 1987 (Box 82)
    - Performance evaluations, 1984-1985 (Box 83)
    - Retirements, 1986 (Box 83)
    - Salary reviews, 1985-1986 (Box 83)
    - San Francisco Office
      - John Florida, 1985-1987 (Box 83)
      - Charlie Martel, 1984-1985 (Box 83)
      - Salary files, 1984 (Box 83)
      - Titles, 1984 (Box 83)
    - SKERP, 1986 (Box 83)
    - Stock options, 1982-1986 (Box 83)
    - Subsidiaries personnel, 1986 (Box 83)
    - Tokyo, Norm Macmaster, 1986 (Box 83)
    - Washington, D.C. Office
      - General files, 1980-1986, (2 folders) (Box 83)
      - Peter Gridley, 1985 (Box 83)
      - Judi Goodhart, 1986 (Box 83)
      - Salary files, 1984 (Box 83)
      - Jeff White, 1985 (Box 83)
- Reports, 1969-1987, (6 boxes)
  Contains charts and prose reports covering topics such as advertising techniques, research, media, industries, and demographics. Also includes annual reports and operations reviews documenting the financial and organizational performance of JWT domestic and international offices. Includes statistics on billings, expenditures, profits and overall personnel performance. Arranged alphabetically by report title.
  - Advertising Agency Image Study (Box 84)
    - First Quarter Report, 1986 (Box 84)
    - Major Findings for 1984 and 1986, 1987 (Box 84)
    - Third Quarter Report, 1986 (Box 84)
  - Agency Ratings, transparencies, 1986 (Box 84)
  - Annual Financial Plan Review, 1987 (Box 84)
  - Annual Reports, 1980-1984 (Box 84)
  - Brokerage Reports, 1986 (Box 84)
  - Compensation Committee Review, 1985-1986, (2 folders) (Box 84)
  - Creative Standards Committee, 1984 (Box 84)
  - Detroit Division May Assessment, 1980 (Box 84)
  - Detroit Internal Audit Report, 1986 Dec. 19 (Box 84)
  - Europe Region, November Reviews, 1986 (Box 84)
  - Financial reports, 1986-1987 (Box 85)
  - Financial reviews, 1984 (Box 85)
  - Five Year History Income Statement, 1981-1985 (Box 85)
  - JWT America Latina November Review, 1986 (Box 85)
  - JWT-USA
    - Personnel Function Report, 1984 (Box 85)
    - Revenue and Cost Trends, 1986-1987 (Box 85)
    - TAAP, 1986 (Box 85)
  - JWT Worldwide Staff Survey: Attitudes to JWT Amongst Executive Staff in the 15 Largest Offices, 1984 (Box 85)
  - Los Angeles Office
    - Internal Audit Report, 1984 June 8 (Box 85)
    - Internal Office Report, 1984 May 23 (Box 85)
  - November Monitoring Report, Controller's Department, 1986 (Box 85)
  - Operating Results, 1985 (Box 85)
  - Operations Reviews
    - 1979, Detroit Division (Box 85)
    - 1980, October Planning Review (Box 85)
    - 1981, Operation Planning Review (Box 85)
    - 1981, 1982 Financial Operating Review (Box 85)
    - 1982 Oct. (Box 86)
    - 1983 Oct. (Box 86)
    - 1984 Aug. 14 (Box 86)
    - 1984 Oct. 26, (2 folders) (Box 86)
    - 1984 Nov., miscellaneous files (Box 86)
    - Financial, 1984 Apr. (Box 86)
    - 1985-1986, general files (Box 86)
      [Includes Thompson Company Peer Review presentation.]
    - 1985 May, (2 folders) (Box 86)
    - 1985 May (Box 87)
    - 1985 July (Box 87)
    - (2 folders) (Box 87)
    - 1985 Oct., (3 folders) (Box 87)
    - 1985 Nov., miscellaneous files (Box 87)
    - 1985, 1986 plan (Box 87)
    - 1986, Asia Pacific (Box 87)
    - 1986, Broulliard (Box 87)
    - 1986, Central Pacific (Box 87)
    - 1986 Nov., Europe (Box 87)
    - 1986, Financial Review and 1987 Preliminary Plan (Box 87)
    - 1986, Latin America (Box 88)
    - 1986, miscellaneous files (Box 88)
    - 1986, Thompson Recruitment Advertising, Inc., (2 folders) (Box 88)
    - 1986 May, (2 folders) (Box 88)
    - 1986 July revision II (Box 88)
    - 1986 Nov., (3 folders) (Box 88)
    - 1987, general files (Box 88)
    - 1987, Canada (Box 88)
  - Organizational and Systems Assessment, 1980 (Box 88)
  - Peer Review, 1985 (Box 89)
  - Positive Operating Actions Implemented in 1986 to Improve Profitability, 1986 (Box 89)
  - Professional Services Group, 1987 Plan and Budget, 1986 (Box 89)
  - Real Estate Study, 1982 (Box 89)
  - Report on Special Audit of European JWT, 1984 (Box 89)
  - Retirement General Fund Report, JWT employees, 1983 (Box 89)
  - San Francisco Office, Internal Audit Report, 1983 (Box 89)
  - Stock Option Reports, 1986 (Box 89)
  - Succession Planning Review, 1986, (3 folders) (Box 89)
  - TV Audience Assessment, 1984-1985 (Box 89)
  - 1986 in Review, (3 folders) (Box 89)
- Subsidiaries 1982-1987, (2 boxes)
  Contains contracts, monthly statements, correspondence notes, charts, minutes, and other documents pertaining to JWT's domestic and European subsidiaries. Original folder titles were maintained and items were arranged alphabetically.
  - Acquisitions, 1985-1987 (Box 90)
  - Begg Dow Priday, 1982-1985 (Box 90)
  - Brouillard Communications, 1985-1987 (Box 90)
  - Collective Subsidiaries, 1986 (Box 90)
  - Euro Advertising, Ltd., 1982-1983, (2 folders) (Box 90)
  - Hawaii, 1984-1985 (Box 90)
  - Hispania, 1985-1987 (Box 90)
  - Hill & Knowlton, 1982-1986, (2 folders) (Box 90)
  - JWT Direct/West, 1985-1987 (Box 91)
  - JWT Field Force, 1982-1987 (Box 91)
  - JWT Healthcare Group, 1986-1987 (Box 91)
  - Ketcham, 1985 (Box 91)
  - Leber-Katz, 1984 (Box 91)
  - Lord Geller/Alfa Romeo Ford Clearance Situation, 1983-1986 (Box 91)
  - Marti-Flores-Prieto & Wachtel, 1983-1986 (Box 91)
  - [Personnel files moved to Personnel Files series.] (Box 91)
  - Survival Anglia, 1982-1986 (Box 91)
  - Tom Sutton International Exchange Program, 1986 (Box 91)
  - Talent Bank, 1984-1985 (Box 91)
  - Teleconferencing, 1984 (Box 91)
  - Thompson Recruitment Advertising, 1986 (Box 91)
  - Training Program, 1982-1984 (Box 91)
  - Troutbeck, 1984-1985, (2 folders) (Box 91)
- Writings and Speeches, 1970-1987 and undated, (2 boxes)
  Contains scripts and notes relating to presentations and speeches given by Jack Peters and other JWT employees, primarily on JWT initiatives and status. Items arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Assessment of Account Planning, 1984 (Box 91)
  - Become the Leading International Advertising Agency: A Plan, 1985 (Box 91)
  - Competitive Analysis presentation, 1986 (Box 92)
  - Defending the Throne: A Competitive Marketing Analysis, 1984 (Box 92)
  - Guide to the T-Plan, 1985 (Box 92)
  - JWT-U.S. Competitive Framework, Where Are We Now?, 1980 (Box 92)
  - New York Society of Security Analysts presentation, 1983 (Box 92)
  - Ogilvy & Mather, People Book, undated (Box 92)
  - Outline for a Public Relations Program for JWT-U.S., 1983 (Box 92)
  - Positive and Negative Factors Impacting on the U.S. Company in 1986, 1986 (Box 92)
  - Revenue Growth, undated (Box 92)
  - Strategic Review presentation, 1985-1987 (Box 92)
  - Supplemental Executive Retirement Plan, 1985 (Box 92)
  - T-Plan: What Is It, How to Use It, 1980 (Box 92)
  - Thoughts on JWT, Jack Peters, 1970-1979 (Box 92)
  - Thomson McKinnon Securities, 1984 (Box 92)
  - 1984 Retention and Growth Plans for Multinational Accounts, 1983 Dec. 8 (Box 92)
- Oversize Materials, 1965-1986, (2 boxes)
  Contains large-format items removed from previous series. Includes several proofs from Ford campaigns in various countries. Also includes report book of the Liggett & Myers account by the Lark Advertising firm.
  - Client files (Box OV 1)
    - Ligget & Myers Incorporated, Lark Advertising, Annual Plan, 1969 (Box OV 1)
  - Administrative files (Box OV 2)
    - Media
      - Black media, 1985 (Box OV 2)
  - Client files
    - General
      - Multinational clients
        - General files, 1984-1986 (Box OV 2)
    - De Beers (International)
      - General files, 1982-1985 (Box OV 2)
    - Ford (Argentina)
      - General files, 1979-1983 (Box OV 2)
    - Ford (Japan)
      - General files, 1979-1983 (Box OV 2)
    - Ford (Melbourne)
      - General files, 1980-1983 (Box OV 2)
    - Ford (Philippines)
      - General files, 1979-1983 (Box OV 2)
    - Ford (U.S.A.)
      - Meeting, 1985 Jan. 14 (Box OV 2)
      - Rolls Royce, 1965 (Box OV 2)
    - U.S Air
      - Target Plan, 1984 (Box OV 2)
  - International offices
    - Caracas
      - General files, 1981-1986 (Box OV 2)
    - Milan
      - General files, 1980-1986 (Box OV 2)
    - Philippines
      - General files, 1981-1986 (Box OV 2)